funny	user_id	review_id	text	business_id	stars	date	useful	cool
0	cjpdDjZyprfyDG3RlkVG3w	VfBHSwC5Vz_pbFluy07i9Q	"My girlfriend and I stayed here for 3 nights and loved it. The location of this hotel and very decent price makes this an amazing deal. When you walk out the front door Scott Monument and Princes street are right in front of you, Edinburgh Castle and the Royal Mile is a 2 minute walk via a close right around the corner, and there are so many hidden gems nearby including Calton Hill and the newly opened Arches that made this location incredible.The hotel itself was also very nice with a reasonably priced bar, very considerate staff, and small but comfortable rooms with excellent bathrooms and showers. Only two minor complaints are no telephones in room for room service (not a huge deal for us) and no AC in the room, but they have huge windows which can be fully opened. The staff were incredible though, letting us borrow umbrellas for the rain, giving us maps and directions, and also when we had lost our only UK adapter for charging our phones gave us a very fancy one for free.I would highly recommend this hotel to friends, and when I return to Edinburgh (which I most definitely will) I will be staying here without any hesitation."	uYHaNptLzDLoV_JZ_MuzUA	5	12/07/2016	0	0
0	oU2SSOmsp_A8JYI7Z2JJ5w	llmdwOgDReucVoWEry61Lw	Location is everything and this hotel has it! The reception is inviting and open 24 hours. They are very helpful and have a lot of patience answering all my questions about where to go etc. there is also a lounge open 24 hours with snack-type food. Breakfast is continental-style so if you want heartier fare look elsewhere though you don't have to go far. The bus and train stations are right across the street so it's easy access to the airport or anywhere else you may want to go. Turn uphill to old town or cross the bridge to new town. The room with a view i got was spacious and comfortable though it's a bit of a maze to find it-just follow the signs. The windows are double paned so the room is quiet plus i was on the 5th floor which helps. It's a bit pricey but still one of the best values i found!	uYHaNptLzDLoV_JZ_MuzUA	4	21/08/2016	0	0
0	0xtbPEna2Kei11vsU-U2Mw	DuffS87NaSMDmIfluvT83g	"gute lage im stadtzentrum. shoppingmeile und sehenswí_rdigkeiten, sowie gute pubs in laufweite. das hotel ist neu, gut gepflegt und hat bemí_htes/nettes personal. ideal fí_r einen kurztrip nach edinburgh. lí_ngere aufenthalte eher nicht, da die zimmer recht klein sind."	uYHaNptLzDLoV_JZ_MuzUA	5	20/11/2013	0	0
0	rW8q706dz5-NnXDzMwVkiw	GvLmUkjUrOyFH8KFnmT1uw	"Erstklassige Lage. Dazu ist alles geschrieben  worden.Wir hatten Zimmer 718 mit Blick auf den Bahnhof. Ist zwar zu laut mit offenen Fenster nachts, aber der Ausblick verzeiht alles. Das Personal ist sehr freundlich und super hilfsbereit. Wer Edinburgh zu Fuíô erkunden mí_chte, ist hier perfekt aufgehoben."	uYHaNptLzDLoV_JZ_MuzUA	5	05/06/2016	0	0
0	yx8vNXUL0D0HS8rUIC7AFA	lGEl24NGj2HVBJrodeXcjg	"Beautiful space, great location, staff rock. Tiny room, but this was expected. Bathroom amazing. Walls, however, paper thin, which is why I can barely string a sentence together in this review."	uYHaNptLzDLoV_JZ_MuzUA	4	21/02/2015	0	0
0	zXnH6W74FAJQ7q7b-NuBsA	cUgvEy5wj7zYE68v1BzzVg	"This is a fairly new property I think. It is a German company and has most of the amenities you would want. It is priced on the budget minded side so it won't break your bank.Location is really good. Near the Royal Mile and Waverley station without being too noisy. Very easy to walk to everything we wanted to do. Has WiFi but we did have to re-log in every day."	uYHaNptLzDLoV_JZ_MuzUA	4	07/07/2013	0	0
0	c5yp5hxwC1N98MjbV2LyWQ	FSB_BnvysBgH3JYrbFNcgw	"First time at this group of hotels. Pretty new, only one in UK, another to open in Edinburgh and one in London. Rooms not very big but great price and location for a weekend in Edinburgh. Rooms clean, comfortable, good shower and free wifi!"	uYHaNptLzDLoV_JZ_MuzUA	4	27/04/2013	2	2
0	xJisL5w4wOgiYLokGMT_IA	dhl3ZW9aAEX_T7_um5tfaQ	"Location location location! Motel One is just right in the middle of everything. To one side you have the New town and the main trains station ( and right in front of the airport bus)  and on the other side the beautiful old town of Edinburg. The room was small but clean and with all you need. The bathroom was also small but nice and clean and the shower was big and good! Next to the bed there is a European plug (CC 7/7) so we actually didn't need to use our adapter. The beed was to hard for my back and I prefer the bed more soft, but I will still come back to Edinburgh and Motel One."	uYHaNptLzDLoV_JZ_MuzUA	4	13/04/2015	2	0
1	tgV6tsYQ66DZ3LQKvtC6cw	JQJvnM3p-3eML05eKcTgiw	"A hotel that has all the basics that you'd need - no additional fuss. For the price we paid, I'd say this place is actually pretty good value. The location is super central and it's easy to get to everywhere from here! It's also right next to the airport shuttle bus and train station, so transport is also easy. The insides is a bit of a maze depending on where your room is located - you may have to go down to go up to go back down again to get to your room! But no bother, it's good for walking off the chips and sobering from your drinks."	uYHaNptLzDLoV_JZ_MuzUA	4	08/11/2016	1	1
0	Q-3YCVywc03w56wYtGlKvg	6JF4WfHgwYrrdZ2VeYtnFw	"Stayed here for two nights, costs was Œ£109 per night for two people sharing a room which was not a budget price for what felt like budget rooms. Firstly they don't have any twin rooms in the hotel which would be preferable when I was sharing with a friend not my lover! There is only one small bin which is located in the bathroom.  No soap, which I find ridiculous, only toiletries were a dual shower gel/hair wash. There was a hairdryer but no wardrobes or drawers. Room was also very cold. Now for the positive, the location is very good, close to princes street and St. Andrews square. The staff are very helpful and the bar is 24 hours. Don't bother with the breakfast which is Œ£9.50 each for a continental breakfast where you can easily get a cooked breakfast in any one of the cafes in Cockburn Street, which is adjacent to this hotel. If I go to Edinburgh again I will book a different hotel."	uYHaNptLzDLoV_JZ_MuzUA	3	27/07/2015	1	0
0	Cx4UCow0zQgFQOp47RRRaA	fbVYETRuWDw8QnpimpGMpg	"Well, i like the idea of Motel One. Always in the center of the city, somehow modern design, good beds. No fancy unnecessary stuff. All of this is true for this motel one in Edinburgh. Perfectly located even if it's hard to discover. Breakfast is ok, but not more. Service is friendly. No twin rooms available.."	uYHaNptLzDLoV_JZ_MuzUA	4	07/05/2014	1	0
0	eqWEgMH-DCP74i82BEAZzw	lobj38NgaokqVseN8_nn6g	"I really do love the Germans. This chain is spreading fast over there and they're bringing their efficiency and attention to detail with them here. Motel One is, as the name suggests, aimed at the budget market. Rates for this venue range from approximately Œ£69/night up. I booked ahead and appreciated the completely free reservation process with room guaranteed until 6pm on the day of arrival. If you give your credit card details, it's reserved beyond that time.Location is excellent! If you exit from the Market St side of Waverly and turn right it's maybe 3 minutes away. It would be very hard to have it closer. That also makes it very close to the castle and Princes St. Welcome was warm and check-in easy. The lobby area is pretty small but clean and cosy with sweets, maps etc. There's a bar area down a few steps where they also serve the buffet breakfast each morning.My room was the cheapest version and was internal, facing onto a courtyard. It had no view and was quite dark, but quiet. Everything was completely spotless. The bathroom was small but well designed and had a great shower. Bed was comfy with 2 single duvets. So continental, don't you know? I appreciated the tea and coffee making facilities (I'm like a beast without them), the decent sized TV and the free wifi. The hanging storage facilities are limited but it was fine for a few days. Random: hands down the best hotel hairdryer I have ever used. And one of the best dryers in general-called a Black Mambo. It was worth staying there for that alone. Well, you know, also the really good value and the pristine conditions. But definitely the hairdryer."	uYHaNptLzDLoV_JZ_MuzUA	4	26/02/2015	1	0
0	d0DGZRp6lHXGECJSc_nn-A	ysfjtAWreLoy7um8WTb8xA	"Motel One sets the standard for budget hotels. I stayed at the Dusseldorf branch a while ago so when I saw one in Edinburgh, I knew this was the place to book. We managed to get a reservation during the Edinburgh Fringe Festival and only booked a few weeks before. We did pay a premium over the normal rate but given the crowds in the city during this time, it was still a good deal compared to other hotels.Staff were all friendly and welcoming, presentable and professional.We received a room upgrade with quite a large room overlooking the bridge crossing Waverley station to Princes St. Despite overlooking a busy road, the room was almost silent thanks to solid double glazing. The room temperature was perfectly controlled with an individual A/C unit. Super clean, modern, uncluttered. Bathroom was similar. No slamming doors or noise in the night. Bonus.Free wifi that works with one log in (doesn't require repeated log ins as some places do) and had decent signal strength.The buffet continental breakfast was also a hit with fresh croissants, danishes, cold cuts, cheese, toast, fruit and yoghurt all well presented, fresh and good quality as was the coffee.If I am looking for a reasonable hotel in a city, Motel One will be by first choice."	uYHaNptLzDLoV_JZ_MuzUA	5	21/08/2015	1	1
0	IpLZ7RevQrFPJWYc9Gxymg	OF1ToqGAubsWGri5iad15w	"Had Continental style breakfast here a short distance from Waverley Station as I had half hour before a train home and wanted to try somewhere new. Motel1One is nearby and a easy two minute walk, slightly uphill towards the castle from the station. On entry it's modern, cosy has tons of cool yet bright pastel and mochilato colours to accommodate your cold wintertime self. Wooden floors, warm rugs, sheepskins on the sofas, slate walls and oak barrelled tables, with slight distinct Scottish themes due to their tartan furnished accessories completes the feel.I sat in One Lounge, had tea and food self served for well under Œ£10, you know bran, meats cheese and croissant that sort of stuff. With a copy of local newspaper in hand I really needed to eat, stay warm and access wifi, the reasons I came in.Some hotels in the city give you access to wifi if your a paying guest, but repeated attempts to access their wifi even with staff help, eventually gave access but in German. On going to reception again for additional help the staff were great got the correct website for me, but still no luck.Hmmm, by the time this was all done I came back to cold tea and didn't really have time now to finish a second cup of hot Earl Grey, so sorry to staff for removing an almost full cup of tea. Great place though nice breakfast and funky decor especially the plasma tv displaying a roasting log fire in reception, but sadly for me no easy access to wifi when badly required.Maybe next time I will endeavour to try food against technology!"	uYHaNptLzDLoV_JZ_MuzUA	3	07/12/2013	1	0
0	kzyLOqiJvyw_FWFTw2rjiQ	ByRzJ8rF2KJWLr-cUNU6EA	"This place is horrible, we were so excited to try it since I got a gift card for my birthday. We went in an ordered are whole meal and they did not except are gift card, because their system was down. Unacceptable, this would have been so helpful if we would have known this prior!!"	jQsNFOzDpxPmOurSWCg1vQ	1	03/06/2017	0	0
